<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Atualizações ICAM - Destaques</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/actualizacoes/destaques/rss.xml</link><description>Sinopses de artigos científicos produzidas pela equipa ICAM.</description><atom:link href="https://icam.org.pt/actualizacoes/destaques/rss.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>pt</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 17:27:47 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Recomendações práticas para o controlo dos diabetes em doentes com COVID-19</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=405</link><description>Practical recommendations for the management of diabetes in patients with COVID-19. Bornstein, et al. The lancet. Diabetes &amp; endocrinology. | 23-Apr-2020</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=405</guid></item><item><title>Comparação de máscaras de tecido e de máscaras cirúrgicas utilizadas por profissionais de saúde</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=404</link><description>A cluster randomised trial of cloth masks compared with medical masks in healthcare workers. MacIntyre, et al. BMJ open. | 22-Apr-2015</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=404</guid></item><item><title>Dinâmicas dos anticorpos (Acs) IgM e IgG anti-SARS-CoV-2 em doentes com COVID-19</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=403</link><description>Dynamics of anti-SARS-Cov-2 IgM and IgG antibodies among COVID-19 patients. Lee, et al. The Journal of infection. | 23-Apr-2020</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=403</guid></item><item><title>Avaliação dos sintomas oculares e tropismo do SARS CoV-2 em doentes com COVID-19</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=402</link><description>Evaluation of ocular symptoms and tropism of SARS-CoV-2 in patients confirmed with COVID-19. Hong, et al. Acta ophthalmologica. | 26-Apr-2020</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=402</guid></item><item><title>Análise aerodinâmica do SARS CoV-2 em dois hospitais de Wuhan</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=401</link><description>Aerodynamic analysis of SARS-CoV-2 in two Wuhan hospitals. Liu, et al. Nature. | 27-Apr-2020</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=401</guid></item><item><title>Revisão do tratamento farmacológico para a infeção por SARS-CoV-2</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=400</link><description>Pharmacologic Treatments for Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19): A Review. Sanders, et al. JAMA. | 13-Apr-2020</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=400</guid></item><item><title>Transmissão da infeção por SARS-CoV-2 numa unidade de enfermagem especializada</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=399</link><description>Presymptomatic SARS-CoV-2 Infections and Transmission in a Skilled Nursing Facility. Arons, et al. The New England journal of medicine. | 24-Apr-2020</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=399</guid></item><item><title>Valor preditivo dos sintomas iniciais para a positividade do teste SARS-CoV-2 entre profissionais de saúde</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=398</link><description>Strong associations and moderate predictive value of early symptoms for SARS-CoV-2 test positivity among healthcare workers, the Netherlands, March 2020. Tostmann, et al. Euro surveillance : bulletin Europeen sur les maladies transmissibles = European communicable disease bulletin. | Apr-2020</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=398</guid></item><item><title>Apresentação alternativa de infeção pelo SARS-CoV-2</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=397</link><description>Varicella-like exanthem associated with COVID-19 in an 8-year-old girl: A diagnostic clue? Genovese, et al. Pediatric dermatology. | 21-Apr-2020</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=397</guid></item><item><title>Papel do Tocilizumab no tratamento da COVID-19</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=396</link><description>Supportive Treatment with Tocilizumab for COVID-19: A Systematic Review. Alzghari and Acuña. Journal of clinical virology : the official publication of the Pan American Society for Clinical Virology. | 21-Apr-2020</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=396</guid></item></channel></rss>