<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Atualizações ICAM - Destaques</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/actualizacoes/destaques/rss.xml</link><description>Sinopses de artigos científicos produzidas pela equipa ICAM.</description><atom:link href="https://icam.org.pt/actualizacoes/destaques/rss.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>pt</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 16:17:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Possível associação entre a vacinação BCG e a COVID-19</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=394</link><description>Connecting BCG Vaccination and COVID-19: Additional Data Dayal D, Gupta S.medRxiv preprint  | 08-Apr-2020</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=394</guid></item><item><title>Exantema como sintoma de apresentação de pneumonia COVID-19</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=391</link><description>A Case of COVID-19 Pneumonia in a Young Male with Full Body Rash as a Presenting Symptom. Hunt and Koziatek. Clinical practice and cases in emergency medicine. | 28-Mar-2020</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=391</guid></item><item><title>Púrpura trombocitopénica imune numa doente com COVID-19</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=389</link><description>Immune Thrombocytopenic Purpura in a Patient with Covid-19. Zulfiqar, et al. The New England journal of medicine. | 15-Apr-2020</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=389</guid></item><item><title>Descrição de doentes com coagulopatia e COVID-19 </title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=388</link><description>Coagulopathy and Antiphospholipid Antibodies in Patients with Covid-19. Zhang, et al. The New England journal of medicine. | 23-Apr-2020</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=388</guid></item><item><title>Teste rápido para deteção combinada de anticorpos IgM e IgG contra o SARS-CoV2</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=387</link><description>Development and clinical application of a rapid IgM-IgG combined antibody test for SARS-CoV-2 infection diagnosis. Li, et al. Journal of medical virology. | 27-Feb-2020</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=387</guid></item><item><title>Considerações da AEMPS sobre a utilização de medicamentos para a COVID-19 </title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=386</link><description>Tratamientos disponibles para el manejo de la infección respiratoria por SARS-CoV-2. Agencia Española del Medicamento y Productos Sanitarios Agencia Española del Medicamento y Productos Sanitarios | 19-Mar-2020</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=386</guid></item><item><title>COVID-19 - Incidência elevada de complicações trombóticas em doentes na UCI</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=384</link><description>Incidence of thrombotic complications in critically ill ICU patients with COVID-19. Klok, et al. Thrombosis research. | 10-Apr-2020</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=384</guid></item><item><title>A anticoagulação reduz a mortalidade em doentes COVID-19 com coagulopatia</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=383</link><description>Anticoagulant treatment is associated with decreased mortality in severe coronavirus disease 2019 patients with coagulopathy. Tang, et al. Journal of thrombosis and haemostasis : JTH. | 27-Mar-2020</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=383</guid></item><item><title>Papel da heparina no tratamento de doentes COVID-19 </title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=382</link><description>Heparin therapy improving hypoxia in COVID-19 patients - a case series Negri et al.  medRxiv preprint  | 22-Apr-2020</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=382</guid></item><item><title>Alterações relevantes na coagulação sanguínea de doentes com infeção por SARS-CoV-2</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=381</link><description>Prominent changes in blood coagulation of patients with SARS-CoV-2 infection. Han, et al. Clinical chemistry and laboratory medicine. | 16-Mar-2020</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=381</guid></item></channel></rss>