<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Atualizações ICAM - Tratamento</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/actualizacoes/tratamento/rss.xml</link><description>Sinopses de artigos científicos produzidas pela equipa ICAM.</description><atom:link href="https://icam.org.pt/actualizacoes/tratamento/rss.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>pt</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 13:49:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Tratamento da ARDS em doentes com COVID-19 (opinião)</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=284</link><description>Treatment for severe acute respiratory distress syndrome from COVID-19. Matthay, et al. The Lancet. Respiratory medicine. | 20-Mar-2020</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=284</guid></item><item><title>Eficácia e segurança da oxigenação nasal de alto fluxo (HFNO) vs oxigenação com máscara padrão durante a intubação por fibroscopia</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=283</link><description>High-flow nasal-oxygenation-assisted fibreoptic tracheal intubation in critically ill patients with COVID-19 pneumonia: a prospective randomised controlled trial. Wu, et al. British journal of anaesthesia. | 19-Mar-2020</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=283</guid></item><item><title>Aumento do rácio ventilatório em doentes COVID-19 a fazerem VMI e com hipercápnia: o que fazer?</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=281</link><description>Ventilatory Ratio in Hypercapnic Mechanically Ventilated Patients with COVID-19 Associated ARDS. Liu, et al. American journal of respiratory and critical care medicine. | 23-Mar-2020</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=281</guid></item><item><title>Indicações, timing e implementação da oxigenação extracorporal (ECMO) em doentes COVID-19</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=280</link><description>Extracorporeal membrane oxygenation support in 2019 novel coronavirus disease: indications, timing, and implementation. Li, et al. Chinese medical journal. | 28-Feb-2020</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=280</guid></item><item><title>COVID-19 - Incidência elevada de complicações trombóticas em doentes na UCI</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=384</link><description>Incidence of thrombotic complications in critically ill ICU patients with COVID-19. Klok, et al. Thrombosis research. | 10-Apr-2020</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=384</guid></item><item><title>A anticoagulação reduz a mortalidade em doentes COVID-19 com coagulopatia</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=383</link><description>Anticoagulant treatment is associated with decreased mortality in severe coronavirus disease 2019 patients with coagulopathy. Tang, et al. Journal of thrombosis and haemostasis : JTH. | 27-Mar-2020</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=383</guid></item><item><title>Tratamento anti-hipertensivo com IECA/ARA de doentes com COVID-19 complicados por hipertensão</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=376</link><description>Antihypertensive treatment with ACEI/ARB of patients with COVID-19 complicated by hypertension. Li, et al. Hypertension research : official journal of the Japanese Society of Hypertension. | 30-Mar-2020</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=376</guid></item><item><title>Interrupção da terapêutica dos IECA/ARA, opinião da Sociedade Europeia de Cardiologia (ESC)</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=369</link><description>SARS-CoV2: should inhibitors of the renin-angiotensin system be withdrawn in patients with COVID-19? Kuster, et al. European heart journal. | 20-Mar-2020</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=369</guid></item><item><title>Suporte Avançado de Vida (SAV) e Suporte Básico de Vida (SBV) na abordagem a doentes suspeitos ou confirmados de infeção por SARS-Cov-2 (COVID-19) - algoritmos e sua adaptação à presente realidade</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=362</link><description>Interim Guidance for Basic and Advanced Life Support in Adults, Children, and Neonates With Suspected or Confirmed COVID-19: From the Emergency Cardiovascular Care Committee and Get With the Guidelines Edelson, et al. Circulation. | 09-Apr-2020</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=362</guid></item><item><title>Eficácia do remdesivir e da cloroquina na inibição do SARS-CoV-2 in vitro </title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=285</link><description>Remdesivir and chloroquine effectively inhibit the recently emerged novel coronavirus (2019-nCoV) in vitro. Wang, et al. Cell research. | Mar-2020</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=285</guid></item></channel></rss>