<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Atualizações ICAM - Clínica e Diagnóstico</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/actualizacoes/clinica-e-diagnostico/rss.xml</link><description>Sinopses de artigos científicos produzidas pela equipa ICAM.</description><atom:link href="https://icam.org.pt/actualizacoes/clinica-e-diagnostico/rss.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>pt</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 16:17:06 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Garantir um controlo metabólico precoce e completo de todos os doentes afetados pela COVID-19</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=356</link><description>Endocrine and metabolic link to coronavirus infection. Bornstein, et al. Nature reviews. Endocrinology. | 02-Apr-2020</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=356</guid></item><item><title>A COVID-19 e o sistema cardiovascular: implicações no tratamento</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=355</link><description>COVID-19 and the cardiovascular system. Zheng, et al. Nature reviews. Cardiology. | May-2020</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=355</guid></item><item><title>A COVID-19 não provoca uma síndrome de dificuldade respiratória aguda típica</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=346</link><description>Covid-19 Does Not Lead to a "Typical" Acute Respiratory Distress Syndrome. Gattinoni, et al. American journal of respiratory and critical care medicine. | 30-Mar-2020</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=346</guid></item><item><title>COVID-19 e doenças cardiovasculares: devemos iniciar ou continuar a terapêutica com IECAs ou ARAs?</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=331</link><description>Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19) and Cardiovascular Disease. Clerkin, et al. Circulation. | 21-Mar-2020</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=331</guid></item><item><title>Recorrência de análise positiva para o ARN do SARS-CoV-2: relato de caso.</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=303</link><description>Recurrence of positive SARS-CoV-2 RNA in COVID-19: A case report. Chen, et al. International journal of infectious diseases : IJID : official publication of the International Society for Infectious Diseases. | 05-Mar-2020</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=303</guid></item><item><title>Epidemiologia e características clínicas da pneumonia por 2019-nCoV</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=301</link><description>Epidemiological and clinical characteristics of 99 cases of 2019 novel coronavirus pneumonia in Wuhan, China: a descriptive study. Chen, et al. Lancet (London, England). | 15-Feb-2020</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=301</guid></item><item><title>Origem, transmissão e terapias clínicas da COVID-19: uma revisão.</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=296</link><description>The origin, transmission and clinical therapies on coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) outbreak - an update on the status. Guo, et al. Military Medical Research. | 13-Mar-2020</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=296</guid></item><item><title>Prevalência de SARS-CoV-2 em doentes assintomáticos e com imagiologia por TC negativa</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=278</link><description>Asymptomatic SARS-CoV-2 infected patients with persistent negative CT findings. Ling, et al. European journal of radiology. | May-2020</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=278</guid></item><item><title>Características epidemiológicas e clínicas da pneumonia por COVID-19 em 138 doentes internados em Wuhan</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=275</link><description>Clinical Characteristics of 138 Hospitalized Patients With 2019 Novel Coronavirus-Infected Pneumonia in Wuhan, China. Wang, et al. JAMA. | 07-Feb-2020</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=275</guid></item><item><title>Características clínicas da pneumonia por co-infeção com SARS-CoV-2 e vírus da influenza</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=269</link><description>The clinical characteristics of pneumonia patients coinfected with 2019 novel coronavirus and influenza virus in Wuhan, China. Ding, et al. Journal of medical virology. | 20-Mar-2020</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=269</guid></item></channel></rss>