<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Atualizações ICAM - Prevenção</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/actualizacoes/prevencao/rss.xml</link><description>Sinopses de artigos científicos produzidas pela equipa ICAM.</description><atom:link href="https://icam.org.pt/actualizacoes/prevencao/rss.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>pt</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 13:49:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Proteção individual durante a intubação e ventilação durante o surto de COVID-19</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=367</link><description>Intubation and Ventilation amid the COVID-19 Outbreak: Wuhan's Experience. Meng, et al. Anesthesiology. | 26-Mar-2020</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=367</guid></item><item><title>Prevenção da transmissão do SARS-CoV-2 em centros de diálise: lições da primeira fase da epidemia na Lombardia</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=338</link><description>Practical indications for the prevention and management of SARS-CoV-2 in ambulatory dialysis patients: lessons from the first phase of the epidemics in Lombardy. Rombolà, et al. Journal of nephrology. | Apr-2020</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=338</guid></item><item><title>Persistência do coronavírus nas superfícies e inativação por desinfetantes</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=337</link><description>Persistence of coronaviruses on inanimate surfaces and their inactivation with biocidal agents. Kampf, et al. The Journal of hospital infection. | Mar-2020</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=337</guid></item><item><title>Recomendações para a admissão de doentes com COVID-19 nas unidades de cuidados intensivos e intermédios</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=336</link><description>Recommendations for the admission of patients with COVID-19 to intensive care and intermediate care units (ICUs and IMCUs). Swiss Society Of Intensive Care Medicine. Swiss medical weekly. | 23-Mar-2020</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=336</guid></item><item><title>Estratégia para colmatar falta de hemoderivados durante as 2 primeiras semanas do surto de COVID-19 em Washington</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=307</link><description>Prepare to adapt: Blood supply and transfusion support during the first 2 weeks of the 2019 Novel Coronavirus (COVID-19) pandemic affecting Washington State. Pagano, et al. Transfusion. | 21-Mar-2020</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=307</guid></item><item><title>Irritação cutânea devida à utilização de EPI: abordagem e soluções</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=304</link><description>Behavioral considerations and impact on personal protective equipment use: Early lessons from the coronavirus (COVID-19) pandemic. Kantor. Journal of the American Academy of Dermatology. | May-2020</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=304</guid></item><item><title>Medidas hospitalares relacionadas com cirurgia durante a pandemia COVID-19 num hospital terciário de Singapura</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=290</link><description>Preparing for a COVID-19 pandemic: a review of operating room outbreak response measures in a large tertiary hospital in Singapore. Wong, et al. Canadian journal of anaesthesia = Journal canadien d'anesthesie. | 11-Mar-2020</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=290</guid></item><item><title>O ECDC recomenda a utilização de máscaras em todas as consultas</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=289</link><description>Policies on the use of respiratory protection for hospital health workers to protect from coronavirus disease (COVID-19). Chughtai, et al. International journal of nursing studies. | May-2020</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=289</guid></item><item><title>A utilização de máscaras N95/FFP2 e o risco de transmissão de SARS-CoV-2.</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=288</link><description>Association between 2019-nCoV transmission and N95 respirator use. Wang, et al. The Journal of hospital infection. | 03-Mar-2020</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=288</guid></item><item><title>Recomendações para minimização da geração aerossóis durante os procedimentos de instrumentação das vias aéreas</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=282</link><description>Outbreak of a new coronavirus: what anaesthetists should know. Peng, et al. British journal of anaesthesia. | May-2020</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=282</guid></item></channel></rss>