<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Atualizações ICAM - Prognóstico</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/actualizacoes/prognostico/rss.xml</link><description>Sinopses de artigos científicos produzidas pela equipa ICAM.</description><atom:link href="https://icam.org.pt/actualizacoes/prognostico/rss.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>pt</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 16:17:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>A trombocitopénia está associada às apresentações graves da COVID-19 (meta-análise)</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=328</link><description>Thrombocytopenia is associated with severe coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) infections: A meta-analysis. Lippi, et al. Clinica chimica acta; international journal of clinical chemistry. | 13-Mar-2020</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=328</guid></item><item><title>O nível da troponina cardíaca I aumenta significativamente em doentes com infeção grave por SARS-CoV-2 (meta-análise)</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=324</link><description>Cardiac troponin I in patients with coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19): Evidence from a meta-analysis. Lippi, et al. Progress in cardiovascular diseases. | 10-Mar-2020</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=324</guid></item><item><title>Valor prognóstico da calcitonina na forma grave da COVID-19 (meta-análise)</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=323</link><description>Procalcitonin in patients with severe coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19): A meta-analysis. Lippi and Plebani. Clinica chimica acta; international journal of clinical chemistry. | Jun-2020</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=323</guid></item><item><title>Rácio plaquetas/linfócitos: um novo indicador para o prognóstico na doença COVID-19?</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=322</link><description>Platelet-to-lymphocyte ratio is associated with prognosis in patients with coronavirus disease-19. Qu, et al. Journal of medical virology. | 17-Mar-2020</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=322</guid></item><item><title>Achados radiológicos em TC torácica e prognóstico da evolução da doença: Score-TC</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=306</link><description>Association of radiologic findings with mortality of patients infected with 2019 novel coronavirus in Wuhan, China. Yuan, et al. PloS one. | 2020</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=306</guid></item></channel></rss>