<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Atualizações ICAM - Fatores de Risco</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/actualizacoes/fatores-de-risco/rss.xml</link><description>Sinopses de artigos científicos produzidas pela equipa ICAM.</description><atom:link href="https://icam.org.pt/actualizacoes/fatores-de-risco/rss.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>pt</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 13:49:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Descrição de doentes com coagulopatia e COVID-19 </title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=388</link><description>Coagulopathy and Antiphospholipid Antibodies in Patients with Covid-19. Zhang, et al. The New England journal of medicine. | 23-Apr-2020</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=388</guid></item><item><title>COVID-19 - Incidência elevada de complicações trombóticas em doentes na UCI</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=384</link><description>Incidence of thrombotic complications in critically ill ICU patients with COVID-19. Klok, et al. Thrombosis research. | 10-Apr-2020</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=384</guid></item><item><title>COVID-19 e doenças cardiovasculares: devemos iniciar ou continuar a terapêutica com IECAs ou ARAs?</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=331</link><description>Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19) and Cardiovascular Disease. Clerkin, et al. Circulation. | 21-Mar-2020</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=331</guid></item><item><title>Terão os doentes com hipertensão arterial e diabetes mellitus um risco aumentado de contrair a COVID-19?</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=330</link><description>Are patients with hypertension and diabetes mellitus at increased risk for COVID-19 infection? Fang, et al. The Lancet. Respiratory medicine. | Apr-2020</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=330</guid></item><item><title>Prevalência de comorbilidades na nova infeção por coronavírus em Wuhan (COVID-19): uma revisão sistemática e meta-análise</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=298</link><description>Prevalence of comorbidities and its effects in coronavirus disease 2019 patients: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Yang, et al. International journal of infectious diseases : IJID : official publication of the International Society for Infectious Diseases. | 12-Mar-2020</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=298</guid></item><item><title>Classificação de doentes graves em função das comorbilidades para uma triagem eficaz e um tratamento mais personalizado</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=297</link><description>Comorbidities and multi-organ injuries in the treatment of COVID-19. Wang, et al. Lancet (London, England). | 21-Mar-2020</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=297</guid></item></channel></rss>