<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Atualizações ICAM - Epidemiologia</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/actualizacoes/epidemiologia/rss.xml</link><description>Sinopses de artigos científicos produzidas pela equipa ICAM.</description><atom:link href="https://icam.org.pt/actualizacoes/epidemiologia/rss.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>pt</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 17:27:44 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Os níveis de vitamina D não parecem estar associados à variação sazonal das taxas de infeção por influenza (modelo matemático)</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=320</link><description>Shortcomings of vitamin D-based model simulations of seasonal influenza. Shaman, et al. PloS one. | 2011</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=320</guid></item><item><title>Viabilidade do controlo de surtos por COVID-19 através do isolamento de casos e rastreio de contatos: A importância do R0 (modelo matemático)</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=311</link><description>Feasibility of controlling COVID-19 outbreaks by isolation of cases and contacts. Hellewell, et al. The Lancet. Global health. | Apr-2020</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=311</guid></item><item><title>O número básico de reprodução R0 para a COVID-19 é superior ao da SARS (revisão sistemática)</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=310</link><description>The reproductive number of COVID-19 is higher compared to SARS coronavirus. Liu, et al. Journal of travel medicine. | 13-Mar-2020</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=310</guid></item><item><title>Número básico de reprodução (R0) e estimativas do impacto da epidemia COVID-19</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=309</link><description>COVID-19 R0: Magic number or conundrum? Viceconte and Petrosillo. Infectious disease reports. | 25-Feb-2020</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=309</guid></item><item><title>Modelo matemático para o cálculo da transmissibilidade do vírus SARS-CoV-2</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=308</link><description>A mathematical model for simulating the phase-based transmissibility of a novel coronavirus. Chen, et al. Infectious diseases of poverty. | 28-Feb-2020</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=308</guid></item><item><title>Temperatura e humidade elevadas reduzem a transmissão de COVID-19</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=273</link><description>High Temperature and High Humidity Reduce the Transmission of COVID-19 Wang J, et al.  (Epub: March 9, 2020; Last revised April 6, 2020). Available at SSRN Library. | 09-Mar-2020</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=273</guid></item><item><title>Estimativas da mortalidade real associada à COVID-19 </title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=341</link><description>Real estimates of mortality following COVID-19 infection. Baud, et al. The Lancet. Infectious diseases. | 12-Mar-2020</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=341</guid></item><item><title>Impacto da disponibilidade de recursos de saúde na mortalidade por COVID-19</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=340</link><description>Potential association between COVID-19 mortality and health-care resource availability. Ji, et al. The Lancet. Global health. | Apr-2020</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=340</guid></item><item><title>Número básico de reprodução (R0) e estimativas do impacto da epidemia COVID-19</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=309</link><description>COVID-19 R0: Magic number or conundrum? Viceconte and Petrosillo. Infectious disease reports. | 25-Feb-2020</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=309</guid></item><item><title>Incidência, casos cumulativos diários e mortalidade da COVID-19 a nível global</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=268</link><description>Global epidemiology of coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19): disease incidence, daily cumulative index, mortality, and their association with country healthcare resources and economic status. Lai, et al. International journal of antimicrobial agents. | 19-Mar-2020</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=268</guid></item></channel></rss>