<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Atualizações ICAM - Populações Especiais</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/actualizacoes/populacoes-especiais/rss.xml</link><description>Sinopses de artigos científicos produzidas pela equipa ICAM.</description><atom:link href="https://icam.org.pt/actualizacoes/populacoes-especiais/rss.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>pt</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 13:49:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Porque se manifesta a COVID-19 de uma forma ligeira em crianças? (Hipóteses)</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=348</link><description>Why is COVID-19 so mild in children? Brodin. Acta paediatrica (Oslo, Norway : 1992). | 25-Mar-2020</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=348</guid></item><item><title>Mortalidade em crianças imunocomprometidas com infeção adenoviral respiratória grave </title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=343</link><description>Immunocompromised Children with Severe Adenoviral Respiratory Infection. Tylka, et al. Critical care research and practice. | 2016</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=343</guid></item><item><title>Características clínicas da COVID-19 em recém-nascidos e crianças </title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=302</link><description>Clinical characteristics of novel coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) in newborns, infants and children. Hong, et al. Pediatrics and neonatology. | Apr-2020</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=302</guid></item><item><title>Características clínicas e achados imagiológicos da infeção por SARS-CoV-2 em crianças</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=299</link><description>SARS-CoV-2 Infection in Children. Lu, et al. The New England journal of medicine. | 23-Apr-2020</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=299</guid></item><item><title>Orientações provisórias da FIGO sobre a COVID-19 durante a gravidez e puerpério </title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=385</link><description>Global interim guidance on coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) during pregnancy and puerperium from FIGO and allied partners: Information for healthcare professionals. Poon, et al. International journal of gynaecology and obstetrics: the official organ of the International Federation of Gynaecology and Obstetrics. | 04-Apr-2020</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=385</guid></item><item><title>O que sabemos até agora sobre a transmissão vertical de COVID-19?</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=372</link><description>Vertical Transmission of Coronavirus Disease 19 (COVID-19) from Infected Pregnant Mothers to Neonates: A Review. Karimi-Zarchi, et al. Fetal and pediatric pathology. | 02-Apr-2020</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=372</guid></item><item><title>Características clínicas da COVID-19 em grávidas no final da gestação, potencial de transmissão vertical e no leite materno</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=300</link><description>Clinical characteristics and intrauterine vertical transmission potential of COVID-19 infection in nine pregnant women: a retrospective review of medical records. Chen, et al. Lancet (London, England). | 07-Mar-2020</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=300</guid></item><item><title>Utilização de imunomodeladores em doentes com doenças dermatológicas graves e COVID-19</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=332</link><description>Advice regarding COVID-19 and use of immunomodulators, in patients with severe dermatological diseases. Rademaker, et al. The Australasian journal of dermatology. | 26-Mar-2020</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=332</guid></item><item><title>COVID-19 e doenças cardiovasculares: devemos iniciar ou continuar a terapêutica com IECAs ou ARAs?</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=331</link><description>Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19) and Cardiovascular Disease. Clerkin, et al. Circulation. | 21-Mar-2020</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=331</guid></item><item><title>Coronavírus e crianças imunossuprimidas: riscos e tratamentos durante a pandemia num centro de Hepatologia</title><link>https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=312</link><description>Coronaviruses and Immunosuppressed Patients: The Facts During the Third Epidemic. D'Antiga. Liver transplantation : official publication of the American Association for the Study of Liver Diseases and the International Liver Transplantation Society. | 20-Mar-2020</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=312</guid></item></channel></rss>