<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Some Testfeed</title><link>http://larskiesow.de/test.atom</link><description>icam</description><atom:link href="http://larskiesow.de/test.atom" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>pt</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2020 16:30:50 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Achados imagiológicos por TC torácica em 919 adultos com COVID-19: uma revisão sistemática</title><link>https://www.icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=1167</link><description>Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19): A Systematic Review of Imaging Findings in 919 Patients.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;14-Mar-2020 Salehi, et al. AJR. American journal of roentgenology.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=1167</guid></item><item><title>Características epidemiológicas e clínicas da pneumonia por COVID-19 em 138 doentes internados em Wuhan</title><link>https://www.icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=1166</link><description>Clinical Characteristics of 138 Hospitalized Patients With 2019 Novel Coronavirus-Infected Pneumonia in Wuhan, China.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;07-Feb-2020 Wang, et al. JAMA.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=1166</guid></item><item><title>Persistência do ARN viral de SARS-CoV-2 em amostras fecais após 2 testes negativos em amostras do trato respiratório</title><link>https://www.icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=1165</link><description>Prolonged presence of SARS-CoV-2 viral RNA in faecal samples.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;May-2020 Wu, et al. The lancet. Gastroenterology &amp; hepatology.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=1165</guid></item><item><title>Temperatura e humidade elevadas reduzem a transmissão de COVID-19</title><link>https://www.icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=1164</link><description>High Temperature and High Humidity Reduce the Transmission of COVID-19&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;09-Mar-2020 Wang J, et al.  (Epub: March 9, 2020; Last revised April 6, 2020). Available at SSRN Library.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=1164</guid></item><item><title>O domínio de ligação ao recetor (RBD) do SARS-CoV-2 tem maior afinidade de ligação à ECA2 que o do SARS-CoV.</title><link>https://www.icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=1163</link><description>Structure analysis of the receptor binding of 2019-nCoV.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;17-Feb-2020 Chen, et al. Biochemical and biophysical research communications.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=1163</guid></item><item><title>Anticorpos policlonais de ratinho para o SARS-CoV inibem a entrada nas células através do bloqueio da gp SPIKE do SARS-CoV-2</title><link>https://www.icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=1162</link><description>Structure, Function, and Antigenicity of the SARS-CoV-2 Spike Glycoprotein.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;16-Apr-2020 Walls, et al. Cell.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=1162</guid></item><item><title>O SARS-CoV-2 é um novo beta-coronavírus que apresenta uma sequência com 79% de homologia com o SARS-CoV e 50% com o MERS-CoV</title><link>https://www.icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=1161</link><description>Genomic characterisation and epidemiology of 2019 novel coronavirus: implications for virus origins and receptor binding.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;22-Feb-2020 Lu, et al. Lancet (London, England).</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=1161</guid></item><item><title>Características clínicas da pneumonia por co-infeção com SARS-CoV-2 e vírus da influenza</title><link>https://www.icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=1160</link><description>The clinical characteristics of pneumonia patients coinfected with 2019 novel coronavirus and influenza virus in Wuhan, China.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;20-Mar-2020 Ding, et al. Journal of medical virology.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=1160</guid></item><item><title>Incidência, casos cumulativos diários e mortalidade da COVID-19 a nível global</title><link>https://www.icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=1159</link><description>Global epidemiology of coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19): disease incidence, daily cumulative index, mortality, and their association with country healthcare resources and economic status.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;19-Mar-2020 Lai, et al. International journal of antimicrobial agents.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=1159</guid></item><item><title>Identificação e sequenciação do novo coronavirus (SARS-CoV-2)</title><link>https://www.icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=1158</link><description>Identification of Coronavirus Isolated from a Patient in Korea with COVID-19.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Feb-2020 Kim, et al. Osong public health and research perspectives.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.icam.org.pt/revisions/?id=1158</guid></item></channel></rss>